<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Generated by iWisdom 2.30 available from PowerSurgePub.com -->
<pw:wisdom xmlns:pw="http://www.powersurgepub.com/xml/wisdom">
  <pw:item>
    <pw:item-id>
      33
    </pw:item-id>
    <pw:category>
      <pw:category1>
        Music
      </pw:category1>
      <pw:category2>
        Rock
      </pw:category2>
    </pw:category>
    <pw:category>
      <pw:category1>
        Reason to Rock
      </pw:category1>
    </pw:category>
    <pw:title>
      Records we made together in the sixties
    </pw:title>
    <pw:file-name>
      records_we_made_together_in_the_sixties
    </pw:file-name>
    <pw:body>
      <p>
        These days most engineers confronted with a displeasing sound reach for the knobs on the console and tweak the high, mid or low frequencies. When that process is inflicted on more and more tracks of a multi-channel recording the sound passes through dozens of transistors, resulting in a narrower, more confined sound. With the added limitations of digital sound, you end up with a bright and shiny, thin and two-dimensional recording. To my ears anyway.
      </p>
      <p>
        When John [Wood] heard a sound he didn't like, he would lift his bulky frame off the chair and lumber down the stairs, muttering all the way. I began to be able to predict whether he was going to try a different microphone, reposition the existing one or shift the offending musician to another part of the studio. When I listen to records we made together in the sixties, I can still hear the air in the studio and the full dimension of the sounds the musicians created for us. I can hear the depth of Nick Drake's breath as well as his voice, the grit in the crude strings of Robin Williamson's <cite>gimbri</cite> and Dave Mattacks' drum technique spread out warmly in aural Technicolor across the stereo spectrum.
      </p>
    </pw:body>
    <pw:rating>
      Medium
    </pw:rating>
    <pw:pages>
      204-205
    </pw:pages>
    <pw:author>
      <pw:name>
        Joe Boyd
      </pw:name>
      <pw:last-name>
        Boyd
      </pw:last-name>
      <pw:first-name>
        Joe
      </pw:first-name>
      <pw:file-name>
        joe_boyd
      </pw:file-name>
      <pw:wikipedia-link>
        http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Boyd
      </pw:wikipedia-link>
    </pw:author>
    <pw:source>
      <pw:type>
        Book
      </pw:type>
      <pw:title>
        White Bicycles: Making Music in the 1960s
      </pw:title>
      <pw:publisher>
        Serpent&apos;s Tail
      </pw:publisher>
      <pw:city>
        London
      </pw:city>
      <pw:identifier>
        1852429100
      </pw:identifier>
      <pw:rights>
        Copyright
      </pw:rights>
      <pw:year>
        2006
      </pw:year>
      <pw:owner>
        Joe Boyd
      </pw:owner>
      <pw:file-name>
        white_bicycles_making_music_in_the_1960s
      </pw:file-name>
    </pw:source>
    <pw:date-added>
      2008-11-02T08:12:54-08:00
    </pw:date-added>
  </pw:item>
</pw:wisdom>
