<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Generated by iWisdom 2.30 available from PowerSurgePub.com -->
<pw:wisdom xmlns:pw="http://www.powersurgepub.com/xml/wisdom">
  <pw:item>
    <pw:item-id>
      167
    </pw:item-id>
    <pw:category>
      <pw:category1>
        Thought
      </pw:category1>
    </pw:category>
    <pw:title>
      The Celestial Teapot
    </pw:title>
    <pw:file-name>
      the_celestial_teapot
    </pw:file-name>
    <pw:body>
      <p>
        Many orthodox people speak as though it were the business of skeptics to disprove received dogmas rather than of dogmatics to prove them. This is, of course, a mistake. If I were to suggest that between the Earth and Mars there is a china teapot revolving about the sun in an elliptical orbit, nobody would be able to disprove my assertion provided I were careful to add that the teapot is too small to be revealed even by our most powerful telescopes. But if I were to go on to say that, since my assertion cannot be disproved, it is intolerable presumption on the part of human reason to doubt it, I should rightly be thought to be talking nonsense. If, however, the existence of such a teapot were affirmed in ancient books, taught as the sacred truth every Sunday, and instilled into the minds of children at school, hesitation to believe in its existence would become a mark of eccentricity and entitle the doubter to the attentions of the psychiatrist in an enlightened age or of the Inquisitor in an earlier time.
      </p>
    </pw:body>
    <pw:rating>
      Medium
    </pw:rating>
    <pw:author>
      <pw:name>
        Bertrand Russell
      </pw:name>
      <pw:last-name>
        Russell
      </pw:last-name>
      <pw:first-name>
        Bertrand
      </pw:first-name>
      <pw:file-name>
        bertrand_russell
      </pw:file-name>
      <pw:wikipedia-link>
        http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bertrand_Russell
      </pw:wikipedia-link>
    </pw:author>
    <pw:source>
      <pw:type>
        Essay
      </pw:type>
      <pw:title>
        Is There A God?
      </pw:title>
      <pw:year>
        1952
      </pw:year>
      <pw:file-name>
        is_there_a_god
      </pw:file-name>
    </pw:source>
    <pw:date-added>
      2007-09-08T10:21:56-07:00
    </pw:date-added>
  </pw:item>
</pw:wisdom>
