<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Generated by iWisdom 2.30 available from PowerSurgePub.com -->
<pw:wisdom xmlns:pw="http://www.powersurgepub.com/xml/wisdom">
  <pw:item>
    <pw:item-id>
      198
    </pw:item-id>
    <pw:category>
      <pw:category1>
        Spirituality
      </pw:category1>
    </pw:category>
    <pw:title>
      A Short and Simple List
    </pw:title>
    <pw:file-name>
      a_short_and_simple_list
    </pw:file-name>
    <pw:body>
      <p>
        Let me start with a short and simple list. This is not the last word on the topic, but the first word, a simple list of suggestions to get the conversation going. Most of the great wisdom traditions agree that: 
      </p>
      <p>
        1. Spirit, by whatever name, exists. 
      </p>
      <p>
        2. Spirit, although existing out there, is found in here, or revealed within to the open heart and mind. 
      </p>
      <p>
        3. Most of us don't realize this Spirit within, however, because we are living in a world of sin, separation, or duality -- that is, we are living in a fallen, illusory, or fragmented state. 
      </p>
      <p>
        4. There is a way out of this fallen state (of sin or illusion or disharmony), there is a Path to our liberation. 
      </p>
      <p>
        5. If we follow this Path to its conclusion, the result is a Rebirth or Enlightenment, a direct experience of Spirit within and without, a Supreme Liberation, which 
      </p>
      <p>
        6. marks the end of sin and suffering, and 
      </p>
      <p>
        7. manifests in social action of mercy and compassion on behalf of all sentient beings.
      </p>
      <p>
        Does a list something like that make sense to you? Because if there are these general spiritual patterns in the cosmos, at least wherever human beings appear, then this changes everything. You can be a practicing Christian and still agree with that list; you can be a practicing Neopagan and still agree with that list.
      </p>
    </pw:body>
    <pw:rating>
      Medium
    </pw:rating>
    <pw:author>
      <pw:name>
        Ken Wilber
      </pw:name>
      <pw:last-name>
        Wilber
      </pw:last-name>
      <pw:first-name>
        Ken
      </pw:first-name>
      <pw:file-name>
        ken_wilber
      </pw:file-name>
      <pw:wikipedia-link>
        http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Wilber
      </pw:wikipedia-link>
    </pw:author>
    <pw:source>
      <pw:type>
        Web Page
      </pw:type>
      <pw:title>
        Beliefnet
      </pw:title>
      <pw:minor-title>
        Why Do Religions Teach Love and Yet Cause So Much War?
      </pw:minor-title>
      <pw:link>
        http://www.beliefnet.com/story/141/story_14148_1.html
      </pw:link>
      <pw:file-name>
        beliefnet
      </pw:file-name>
    </pw:source>
    <pw:date-added>
      2007-02-10T15:26:31-08:00
    </pw:date-added>
  </pw:item>
</pw:wisdom>
